How exactly does this poison spread into the body?
كيف بالضبط ينتشر هذا السم في الجسم؟
The poisonous centipede he brought back from the south
حريش سامة أحضره من الجنوب
carries a large amount of poisonous powder
يحمل كمية كبيرة من المسحوق السام
that can be transmitted through the air,
التي يمكن أن تنتقل عن طريق الهواء ،
causing people to hallucinate,
تسبب في الهلوسة ،
become confused
أصبح مشوش التفكير
and be manipulated or killed by him.
ويتم التلاعب به أو قتله.
Madam Su has gone mad.
لقد جن جنون سيدتي سو.
The physician said
قال الطبيب
she doesn't have many days left.
لم يتبق لها أيام كثيرة.
What goes around comes around.
ما حدث حولنا ياتينا.
I just hope
أنا فقط أتمنى
that Ruyan can rest in peace.
أن رويان يمكن أن يرقد بسلام.
Well,
نحن سوف،
it's a dangerous world.
إنه عالم خطير.
Are you going to brag and say
هل ستتباهى وتقول
you're going back to the palace?
ستعود إلى القصر؟
Does he really think he's a commoner?
هل يعتقد حقًا أنه من عامة الشعب؟
Won't he return to the palace?
ألا يعود إلى القصر؟
=Mysterious Tales of Chang'an=
= حكايات تشانغآن الغامضة =
=Episode 7=
= الحلقة 7 =
Who's there?
من هناك؟
Anyone there?
أي شخص هناك؟
Why did it catch fire all of a sudden?
لماذا اشتعلت النيران فجأة؟
Let's check over there.
دعنا نتحقق هناك.
Are you sure you were alone
هل أنت متأكد أنك كنت بمفردك
when the carriage caught fire?
عندما اشتعلت النيران في العربة؟
Yes.
نعم.
Think about it again.
فكر في الأمر مرة أخرى.
Is there anything you've missed?
هل فاتك شيء؟
Any findings?
أي نتائج؟
Not at the moment.
ليس الان.
Keep looking.
استمر في البحث.
All right.
حسنا.
Is Zhang Xiaomeng here?
هل Zhang Xiaomeng هنا؟
There she is.
ها هي ذا.
You're here.
أنت هنا.
Chief Shen.
رئيس شين.
Are you here this time
هل انت هنا هذه المرة
to take over from your grandfather?
لتتولى من جدك؟
I told my grandfather I wanted to find a proper job.
أخبرت جدي أنني أريد أن أجد وظيفة مناسبة.
You are very talented,
انت موهوب جدا،
but we've never had a female constable in the magistracy.
لكن لم يكن لدينا قط شرطية في القضاء.
Have you found a place to live?
هل وجدت مكانا للعيش فيه؟
Let's go.
لنذهب.
I've worked with your grandfather for many years.
لقد عملت مع جدك لسنوات عديدة.
You can stay at my house
يمكنك البقاء في بيتي
and keep my daughter company.
والحفاظ على ابنتي.
I will speak to the magistrate
سوف أتحدث إلى القاضي
about the job.
عن وظيفة.
I've taken a look at the body.
لقد ألقيت نظرة على الجسد.
She was wearing a bracelet.
كانت ترتدي سوار.
So it was not for money.
لذلك لم يكن من أجل المال.
Check again.
تحقق مرة اخرى.
It's a female corpse.
إنها جثة أنثى.
Her hands were tied from behind.
كانت يداها مقيدتان من الخلف.
No trace of struggle.
لا أثر للنضال.
She was probably
ربما كانت
unconscious before the fire.
فاقد للوعي قبل الحريق.
However, the body was too badly damaged
ومع ذلك ، فقد أصيب الجسد بأضرار بالغة
for me to determine the exact time of her death.
بالنسبة لي لتحديد وقت وفاتها بالضبط.
Whether she was
سواء كانت
unconscious or dead
فاقدًا للوعي أو ميتًا
before the fire
قبل النار
depended on the ashes remaining in her lungs.
تعتمد على الرماد المتبقي في رئتيها.
This elaborate, ritualistic killing method
طريقة القتل الشعائرية المتقنة هذه
was never expected to happen again.
لم يكن من المتوقع أن يحدث مرة أخرى.
Again?
مرة أخرى؟
Yes.
نعم.
Just a few months ago,
قبل بضعة أشهر فقط ،
A mother in red
أم باللون الأحمر
went to a relative's house in town
ذهبت إلى منزل أحد الأقارب في المدينة
to borrow a basket of rice.
أن تستعير سلة أرز.
(By the time we got there,)
(بحلول الوقت الذي وصلنا فيه إلى هناك ،)
(she was burnt to the ground as well.)
(تم حرقها على الأرض أيضًا).
(It stank as badly)
(انتشرت بشدة)
(as it does now.)
(كما هو الحال الآن).
(The air was thick with burning ashes.)
(كان الهواء كثيفًا بالرماد المحترق).
(her children were waiting for her to come home and make dinner.)
(كان أطفالها ينتظرون عودتها إلى المنزل وإعداد العشاء).
This is not the first time.
هذه ليست المرة الأولى.
In the previous five years,
في السنوات الخمس الماضية ،
there were six other cases with exactly the same method.
كانت هناك ست حالات أخرى بنفس الطريقة بالضبط.
Each time we had all hands on deck,
في كل مرة كانت لدينا جميع الأيدي على سطح السفينة ،
but we came up
لكننا صعدنا
empty.
فارغة.
The victim in each case was female,
الضحية في كل حالة كانت أنثى ،
all dressed in red
كلهم يرتدون ملابس حمراء
and burnt to ashes
وأحرقوا إلى رماد
early one morning.
في وقت مبكر صباح أحد الأيام.
It's not a revenge murder.
إنها ليست جريمة قتل انتقامية.
There's no connection
لا يوجد اتصال
and the timing is irregular.
والتوقيت غير منتظم.
The first and second cases
الحالتان الأولى والثانية
were two years apart.
كانت متباعدة لمدة عامين.
Then it was gradually shortened.
ثم تم تقصيرها تدريجياً.
It's only been less than six months
لقد مرت أقل من ستة أشهر فقط
between the last one and this one.
بين آخر واحد وهذا.
The killer, as if to satisfy his own emotional needs
القاتل ، وكأنه يشبع احتياجاته العاطفية
or beliefs,
أو المعتقدات ،
created a kind of
خلق نوعا من
fantasy trial
محاكمة خيالية
or law enforcement.
أو تطبيق القانون.
(Sin never ceases in the world.)
(الخطيئة لا تتوقف في العالم).
(Only the law is the best existence.)
(فقط القانون هو أفضل وجود.)
(It ensures the bottom line of society)
(يضمن الحد الأدنى للمجتمع)
(and the bottom line of people.)
(وخلاصة الناس.)
Isn't this disrespectful to the dead?
أليس هذا عدم احترام للموتى؟
Shut up.
اسكت.
This is for solving the case.
هذا لحل القضية.
Not solving the case would be the greatest disrespect to the dead.
عدم حل القضية سيكون أكبر عدم احترام للموتى.
The victims were not killed and relocated,
الضحايا لم يُقتلوا أو يُنقلوا ،
but burnt alive.
لكن احترق حيا.
There was a large amount of charcoal ash in the lung section of the deceased
كانت هناك كمية كبيرة من رماد الفحم في رئة المتوفى
and there was no struggle before death.
ولم يكن هناك صراع قبل الموت.
I assume
انا افترض
she may have been drugged before she died.
ربما تم تخديرها قبل وفاتها.
Councillor Liu.
عضو المجلس ليو.
You said that you received a bloodstained letter
قلت أنك تلقيت رسالة ملطخة بالدماء
at your home the night before last.
في منزلك الليلة السابقة الماضية.
The letter reads that he has a blood feud with you
تقرأ الرسالة أن لديه عداء دم معك
and asks you to bring 200 taels in an envelope
ويطلب منك إحضار 200 تايل في مظروف
and send it to No. 37 Wuliu Street.
وأرسلها إلى رقم 37 شارع Wuliu.
Is it correct?
هل هذا صحيح؟
Your Excellency.
امتيازك.
What I said is true.
ما قلته صحيح.
so yesterday morning
حتى صباح أمس
So you took out 200 tales early yesterday morning
لذا أخرجت 200 حكاية في وقت مبكر من صباح أمس
and had it delivered to that address by a mailman.
وتم تسليمها إلى هذا العنوان عن طريق ساعي البريد.
Yes, it's packed with money.
نعم ، إنها مليئة بالمال.
Then you reported it to the authorities.
ثم أبلغت السلطات بذلك.
When my men arrived at the address,
عندما وصل رجالي إلى العنوان ،
they found it deserted.
وجدوها مهجورة.
The person at the recipient's address was a former butcher
الشخص الموجود في عنوان المستلم جزار سابق
and has been away for many years.
وكان بعيدًا منذ سنوات عديدة.
Councillor Liu.
عضو المجلس ليو.
Are you deceiving me?
هل تخدعني؟
Your Excellency.
امتيازك.
What I said is true.
ما قلته صحيح.
Why are you here?
لماذا أنت هنا؟
Your mission.
مهمتك.
Chuchu.
حلمات.
Let me see you crack this case.
دعني أراك تحطم هذه القضية.
Zhang.
تشانغ.
Who called me Zhang again?
من اتصل بي تشانغ مرة أخرى؟
Official Chu.
تشو الرسمية.
Don't you notice it?
ألا تلاحظ ذلك؟
The disappeared butcher was the recipient
كان الجزار المختفي هو المستلم
of the letter with the pig's blood on it.
الحرف الذي عليه دم الخنزير.
It's all an obscure trick.
إنها خدعة غامضة.
The root of the case was that
كان أصل القضية أن
the culprit wanted the money in the envelope.
الجاني يريد المال في الظرف.
And there is a fixed post
وهناك وظيفة ثابتة
and mailman in every part of the city.
ورجل البريد في كل جزء من المدينة.
Mail is sent and received
يتم إرسال البريد واستلامه
by a regular person.
من قبل شخص عادي.
He is the only one with access to this money.
إنه الوحيد الذي لديه إمكانية الوصول إلى هذه الأموال.
So the mailman
حتى ساعي البريد
is the culprit.
هو الجاني.
I see.
أرى.
What are you waiting for? Arrest him!
ماذا تنتظر؟  اعتقله!
Yes.
نعم.